<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sql on Pedro Junqueira</title>
    <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sql on Pedro Junqueira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>pedro junqueira</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 08:30:23 +0930</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SqlServer in docker in less than 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/sqlserver_in_docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 08:30:23 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/sqlserver_in_docker/</guid>
      <description>Who does not want to spin up an instance of SQL Server Development version?
If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the pain of downloading and following the installation wizard in windows you can have an instance of SQL server 2022 running on your system in less than 5 min in docker.
I am assuming 2 things you already have installed in your computer.
Docker Desktop WSL SQL server management studio This version runs on a linux container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not use pandas use with pyodbc</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/pyodbc_vs_adf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 22:17:57 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/pyodbc_vs_adf/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I published a post on and shared on LinkedIn and had a quite big reaction as an popular PBI influencer commented on my post.
One of the comments by Jesus Jayaro called my attention saying that if pyodbc is used with execute many it is faster than data factory.
So I did a quick research and in reality it is fast I am impressed.
On my quick research I could put together a working script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not use Pandas to load data use Data Factory</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/do-not-use_pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 22:00:46 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/do-not-use_pandas/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote blog post about how to connect pandas to your SQL database and read file from SQL server.
pandas is a fantastic tool to analyse and manipulate data. I use it all the time. It is very efficient if the &amp;ldquo;size&amp;rdquo; of the data is say up to 1 million records and can be done in your local machine or in a VM fairly quick calculations. No problems at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Python Azure SQL DB using Pandas</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/connect-python-azure-sqldb-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 20:58:05 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/connect-python-azure-sqldb-pandas/</guid>
      <description>The other day I wanted to connect pandas to Azure SQL DB and boy took me longer than I wanted. In the end I solved my problem. Although, connecting to DBs always involves more complex things like DB drives and OS dependencies the part I struggled the most was with the connection string 😅. Microsoft, in its documentation, which by the way is good, gives good example and steps on setting up the environnement and how to connect through pyodbc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Docker volumes with a practical example</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/understand-docker-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 06:55:35 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/understand-docker-volume/</guid>
      <description>Docker is here to stay and I see it more and more part of the work of any developer and I am impressed to how Docker can make your life so easy.
This post is not a What is Docker one or an introduction.
You can read it here or just watch this very good video from NetworkChuck then you will have a good grasp of its core concepts and what this is for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
