<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Pedro Junqueira</title>
    <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Pedro Junqueira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>pedro junqueira</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 07:52:24 +0930</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pushing image to local minishift registry</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/pushing_image_to_local_minishift_registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 07:52:24 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/pushing_image_to_local_minishift_registry/</guid>
      <description>I am learning OpenShift as I am using it more and more at work and it has been great fun and I am really enjoying the DevOps space which is giving me new super powers as a developer.
It is not the intent of this post explain OpenShift but in summary is a RedHat product to manage a Kubernetes cluster. There are some peculiarities of OpenShift but it is pretty much Kubernetes in 98% of cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Docker volumes with a practical example</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/understand-docker-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 06:55:35 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/understand-docker-volume/</guid>
      <description>Docker is here to stay and I see it more and more part of the work of any developer and I am impressed to how Docker can make your life so easy.
This post is not a What is Docker one or an introduction.
You can read it here or just watch this very good video from NetworkChuck then you will have a good grasp of its core concepts and what this is for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get a PySpark environment running on Jupyter</title>
      <link>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/data-science-on-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:35:16 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrojunqueira.github.io/blog/posts/data-science-on-docker/</guid>
      <description>Python is a magical language. It is just import from * and then the magic start happening&amp;hellip;
However, not always all run smoothly. Sometimes all that you want is to run code but as part of coding debugging is a constant battle until you get your code running as you wish.
Besides the debugging, you need to set up your development environment that can be very very tedious. Sometime you just want to code and get your job done and you may spend hours and hours just setting up the environnement, importing packages, creating VMs, exporting environment variables, running shell scrips, going 10x to stack overflow and still struggle to make things work fine, then finally you can start writing some code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
